bidswitch.net 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy | BidSwitch

### Privacy Policy

* * *

## Respecting your privacy

_Last updated: 4 May 2018_

* * *

* * *

BidSwitch respects your right to privacy. This Privacy Notice explains who we are, how we collect, share and use personal data about you, and how you can exercise your privacy rights. This Privacy Notice only applies to personal data that we collect through our websites (“ **Websites** ”).

If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your personal data, then please contact us using the contact details provided at the bottom of this Privacy Notice.

* * *

#### Quick links

We recommend that you read this Privacy Notice in full to ensure you are fully informed. However, if you only want to access a particular section of this Privacy Notice, then you can click on the relevant link below to jump to that section.

  * What does BidSwitch do?
  * What information do we collect?
  * What purposes do we use your information for?
  * How do we protect your information?
  * Do we use cookies
  * Do we disclose any information to third parties?
  * International data transfers
  * Data retention
  * Third party links
  * Childrens’ Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance (COPPA)
  * Legal basis for processing personal data
  * Changes to our Privacy Notice
  * How to contact us

* * *

#### What does BidSwitch do?

BidSwitch is a provider of real time online advertising support services, headquartered in Switzerland, but with group companies all around the world. Our services enable buyers and sellers of online media to trade media with each other.

For more information about BidSwitch, please see the “BidSwitch” section of our Website at https://www.bidswitch.com/technology/.

* * *

#### What information do we collect?

**Information that you provide voluntarily:**

We may collect information from you when you register with us on our website, place an inquiry, apply for a job, respond to a survey or visit our websites. When registering on our website you may be asked to provide us with information such as your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, website and company information. The personal data that you are asked to provide, and the reasons why you are asked to provide it, will be made clear to you at the point we ask you to provide your personal data.

* * *

**Information that we collect automatically:**

When you visit our Website, we may collect certain information automatically from your device. In some countries, including countries in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), this information may be considered personal data under applicable data protection laws. Specifically, the information we collect automatically may include information like your IP address, device type, unique device identification numbers, browser-type, broad geographic location (e.g. country or city-level location) and other technical information. We may also collect information about how your device has interacted with our Website, including the pages accessed and links clicked.

Collecting this information enables us to better understand the visitors who come to our Website, where they come from, and what content on our Website is of interest to them. We use this information for our internal analytics purposes and to improve the quality and relevance of our Website to our visitors.

Some of this information may be collected using cookies and similar tracking technology, as explained further under the heading Do we use cookies? below or our full cookie statement, available.

* * *

**Information that we obtain from third party sources:**

From time to time, we may receive personal data about you from third party sources, but only where we have checked that these third parties either have your consent or are otherwise legally permitted or required to disclose your personal data to us.  
The types of information we collect from third parties include where you visit a website that displays advertising provided via one of our advertising technology partners, they may provide us with an extract from a cookie stored by the website that you are visiting to help select advertising or content relevant to your interests.

* * *

#### What purposes do we use your information for?

Any of the personal data that we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs);
  * To improve our website (we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you);
  * To improve customer service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your enquiries, applications and support needs);
  * To administer a survey or other website feature;
  * To send periodic emails; or
  * For any other purpose that will be made obvious to you at the time.

**Note:** If at any time you would like to stop receiving emails or communications from us, you can contact us at [info@bidswitch.net](mailto:) and we will remove you from our database.

* * *

#### How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the security of your personal data. The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal data.

* * *

#### Do we use cookies?

Yes, for more information see our Cookie Statement or to opt-out from our cookie(s), please click [here](http://x.bidswitch.net/opt-out). 

* * *

#### Do we disclose any information to third parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personal data. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. We may provide visitor information to third parties for marketing, advertising or other uses.

We may disclose your personal data to the following categories of third parties:

  * to our group companies, third party services providers and partners [who provide data processing services to us (for example, to support the delivery of, provide functionality on, or help to enhance the security of our Website), or who otherwise process personal data for purposes that are described in this Privacy Notice or notified to you when we collect your personal data].
  * to any competent law enforcement body, regulatory, government agency, court or other third party where we believe disclosure is necessary (i) as a matter of applicable law or regulation, (ii) to exercise, establish or defend our legal rights, or (iii) to protect your vital interests or those of any other person;
  * to an actual or potential buyer (and its agents and advisers) in connection with any actual or proposed purchase, merger or acquisition of any part of our business, provided that we inform the buyer it must use your personal data only for the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Notice;
  * to any other person with your consent to the disclosure.

* * *

#### International data transfers

Your personal data may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country (and, in some cases, may not be as protective).

Specifically, some of our website servers are located in the USA and our group companies and third party service providers and partners operate around the world. This means that when we collect your personal data we may process it in any of these countries.

However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal data will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Notice. For any transfers out of the EEA, we will put in place appropriate safeguards in accordance with European law, such as executing the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of personal data between our group companies, which require all group companies to protect personal data they process from the EEA in accordance with European Union data protection law. We have implemented similar appropriate safeguards with our third party service providers and partners and further details can be provided upon request.

* * *

#### Data retention

We retain personal data we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements). When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal data, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal data has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal data and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

* * *

#### Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

* * *

#### Childrens’ Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance (COPPA)

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA, we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

* * *

#### Legal basis for processing personal data

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal data described above will depend on the personal data concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.

However, we will normally collect personal data from you only (i) where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights; (ii) where we need the personal data to perform a contract with you or (iii) where we have your consent to do so. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal data from you.

If we ask you to provide personal data to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contact with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal data is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal data).

If we collect and use your personal data in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), this interest will normally be to operate our Websites and services; communicating with you as necessary to provide our services to you and for our legitimate commercial interest, for instance, when responding to your queries, improving our platform, undertaking marketing, or for the purposes of detecting or preventing illegal activities. We may have other legitimate interests and if appropriate] we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal data, please contact us using the contact details provided under the How to contact us heading below.

* * *

#### Changes to our Privacy Notice

If we decide to change this Privacy Notice, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Notice modification date at the top of this Notice.

* * *

#### How to contact us

If there are any questions regarding this Privacy Notice or your privacy rights you may contact us at [privacy@bidswitch.net](mailto:privacy@bidswitch.net). The Data Controller of your personal data is BidSwitch GmbH of Bahnhofstrasse 28, Postfach 7563, 6302, Zug, Switzerland. BidSwitch is a member of the IPONWEB Group of companies. For details regarding other Data Controllers in the IPONWEB Group, please see <https://www.iponweb.com/contact>.
